{"tossups": [{"question": "The soldier Liutov performs this action in an effort to prove his toughness to a group of Cossacks in an Isaac Babel story. Konstantin does this in order to provide a gift to impress Nina in a play by Chekhov, but Nina is disgusted by it. One of these actions eventually leads its perpetrator to come across a becalmed ship on which Death and Life-in-Death play dice for the souls of his fellow crewmen. That character describes this action to a wedding guest he waylays. FTP the Ancient Mariner performs what action, also done by the protagonist of \"My First Goose\" and The Seagull", "answer": "killing a bird (accept \"goose\" after first sentence and anti-prompt (say \"more general\") after that if they answer with \"seagull\" or \"albatross\")", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In the first act of this play, The Logician offers a bad example of a syllogism to The Old Gentleman leading him to tell the latter his dog is a cat. The protagonist argues with Dudard, who is a rival for the affections of a typist in this play. The Logician's hat is eventually seen on one of the title characters, another one of which tramples a cat, leading cafe patrons to debate its color and breed. Daisy eventually leaves the protagonist of this play, noting she finds the title creatures attractive. FTP Berenger is the lone holdout in what Eugene Ionesco play, refusing to become one of the tile one-horned animals?", "answer": "Rhinoceros", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Canadian artist Brian Jurgen created a large red one of these objects from second-hand textiles. The top right portion of Childe Hassam's painting The Avenue in the Rain contains several of these objects. Gilbert Baker created one of these objects with eight different colors, including hot pink, although most modern versions only possess six different colors. One work by Jasper Johns is a white one of these objects, and in another Johns work, three of these objects that are on top of each other include the colors red, white, and blue. For 10 points, name these symbolic objects, one of which is proudly held by the central figure in Eugene Delacroix's Liberty Leading the People. ", "answer": "flags [accept specific examples] ", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Ken Perlin, who names a type of this phenomenon useful in computer graphics, also developed its simplex type. For an image, the reduction of this phenomenon can be achieved by Gaussian smoothing. A type of this phenomenon that occurs in resistors is caused by the random thermal motion of electrons, and is called the Johnson-Nyquist type. Although this phenomenon is defined as a disturbance in a system that interferes with the reception of information, the white type can be used to mask unwanted sounds. For 10 points, name this phenomenon that is paired with \"The Signal\" in the title of a Nate Silver book about predictions. ", "answer": "noise", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The post-structuralist thinker Jacques Lacan [luh-KHAN] stated that this structure comprises the discourse of the other and is itself structured like a language. Freud argued that our enjoyment of jokes comes partly from repressed ideas in a book relating jokes to this structure. Carl Jung [YOONG] believed in two layers to this structure, one personal and the other populated by universal concepts like the \"hero\" and the \"quest.\" FTP what is this origination point of automatic mental processes of which people are not aware, and of which Carl Jung posited a \"collective\" type?", "answer": "unconscious", "category": "Social Science"}, {"question": "This man was raised by a woman named Lanike [lah-NEE-kay], who was the sister of a future general of this man named Cleitus [KLI-tus] the Black. One uprising against this man was led by Spitamenes. An army led by this man and his father defeated a coalition army of many of the Greek city-states at the battle of Chaeronea [ker-uh-NEE-uh]. This man's father, Phillip II, allegedly stated,\" My boy, you must find a kingdom big enough for your ambitions\" after this man tamed the horse Bucephalus. For 10 points, name this king of Macedon who won the 333 BC Battle of Issus and also named multiple cities after himself, including the Egyptian seaport of Alexandria. ", "answer": "Alexander the Great [accept Alexander III of Macedon]  ", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Voltaire, in his work Philosophical Letters, contrasted English and French philosophical views by contrasting Newton and this thinker. This man argued that 2+3=5 is a true proposition whether one is dreaming or awake, and thus has a different value from sense information. To consider the latter, he proposed a hard piece of wax which has different sense properties after being placed near a flame. In the same work he discussed the possibility that he was being deceived by a demon in order to place himself in hyperbolic doubt. FTP what thinker in his Meditations on First Philosophy decided the only thing he could truly know is his own existence, which he phrased Cogito ergo sum?", "answer": "Rene Descartes", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "Pressure on a cylindrical column containing these substances can cause the sausage instability. The experiment ALICE at CERN is studying one of these substances composed of free quarks and gluons. The electron temperature of these substances can be determined using a Langmuir probe. These substances circulate in a torus-shaped chamber and are confined by a magnetic field in a tokamak. St. Elmo's fire is one of these substances, which are usually found at very high temperatures. For 10 points, name these ionized gases that are called the fourth state of matter. ", "answer": "plasmas", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The authority created by this document was superseded by the Peirce Patent, as this document was only meant to be temporary. It was necessitated by the signatories northward turn outside the boundaries granted to the Virginia Company by the Council of New England. Now lost, its text is known because of a hand-written copy included in a book published by William Bradford, who was a signatory to this document. Of Plymouth Plantation includes the text of, FTP, what 1620 text, the first governing document of the Plymouth Colony, signed by pilgrims on the namesake ship before landing.", "answer": "Mayflower Compact", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": ". In one statement in the Hadith, Abu Huraira tells Muslims this non-Muhammad figure will slay the pigs and abolish the jizya tax on non-Muslims. Muhammad described an evil entity pretending to be this religious figure as being blind in his right eye and having a red complexion. The Quran describes this figure as one of three who was able to speak from the cradle, which he did in front of Zachariah and others in the Temple as his first miracle. FTP name this prophet whom Muslims believe ascended directly into heaven, with Allah creating a look-alike to be crucified in his place.", "answer": "Jesus or Isa Ibn Maryam", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "This country banned the young-adult novel Into the River by Ted Dawes because of its offensive language and sexual descriptions. The taniko weaving patterns as well as the mythological figures Rangi and Papa were part of the inspiration for an option in an upcoming referendum in this country. Other options include a flag with a koru and several with a silver fern, one of which might replace this country's current flag, which includes the stars of the Southern Cross and has a Union Jack as its canton. John Key is the prime minister of this country, which was originally inhabited by the Maori people. For 10 points, name this country located southeast of Australia. ", "answer": "New Zealand [or Aotearoa from any Maoris] ", "category": "Current Events"}, {"question": "This man used flaming camels to defeat an Indian army with elephants during the conquest of Delhi. This man was treated as a subject by the Yongle Emperor, causing this man to form an alliance with the Northern Yuan dynasty. This man referred to King Henry III of Castile as his very own son, as this man and King Henry had many years of positive diplomatic contact. At the sieges of Aleppo and Damascus, the only people spared by this man were artisans, who were sent back to the city of Samarkand. Early in life, after being shot by a shepherd for trying to steal a sheep, this man became crippled. For 10 points, name this figure from the late 1300s who claimed descent from Genghis Khan and walked with a limp.", "answer": "Timur the Lame (or Tamerlane or Timur Lenk", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This poet wrote of \"a singer everyone has heard\" in \"The Oven Bird.\" Another of his poem's speakers notes his desire to \"unite/[his] avocation and [his] vocation/As two eyes make one in sight\" after refusing an offer by hoboes to chop wood for him. This author of \"Two Tramps in Mud Time\" began one poem \"The land was ours before we were the land's\"; he read that poem from memory at JFK's inauguration. FTP name this author of \"The Gift Outright\" who wrote of a path that \"diverged in a yellow wood\" in \"The Road Not Taken.\"", "answer": "Robert Frost", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The rhythms of this dance are used to depict the \"Dies Irae\" in the final movement of Michael Daugherty's Metropolis Symphony, which is named for a \"red cape.\" Seinajoki, Finland hosts an annual festival dedicated to this dance. In the 1921 movie The Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse, the character Rex Ingram, played by Rudolph Valentino, performed this dance. The music for this dance is played by an ensemble with bandoneons. The lyrics \"Pop! Squish! Six!\" begin a song named for this dance from the musical Chicago that occurs in a \"cell block.\" For 10 points, name this dance popular in Argentina that \"it takes two to\" perform", "answer": "tangos", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "One of these reactions that uses the compound BINAP is named for Noyori and results in asymmetric products. One example of this type of reaction is the conversion of oleic acid to stearic acid. Reactions of this type can be performed with Raney nickel and Lindlar's catalyst. General examples of these reactions include the conversion of carbon-carbon triple bonds to double bonds, and the conversion of an unsaturated fatty acid to a saturated one. For 10 points, name these reactions in which the element with atomic number one is added to multiple bonds", "answer": "hydrogenations [accept forms; prompt on \"reduction\" or \"saturation\" or \"addition\"]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Robert Bateman names an art gallery in this province, which is home to the Girl in a Wetsuit sculpture. Butchart Gardens on the Saanich Peninsula is located near this province's capital. Stanley Park is located in this province, which is the alleged home of the Ogopogo lake monster. Many invertebrate fossils have been found in Burgess Shale in this province. The second-largest Chinatown in North America is located in this province, which is bordered by Alberta to the east. For 10 points, name this province whose capital of Victoria is located on Vancouver Island.", "answer": "British Columbia [or BC]", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "In this year, around 125,000 Cubans came to the US in the Mariel boatlift. John B. Anderson ran as an Independent in this year's presidential election, which included a debate in which a candidate asked, \"Are you better off now than you were four years ago?\" In this year, the Canadian Caper occurred, in which six American diplomats escaped Iran using fake visas. Mount St. Helens erupted in this year, and Moscow hosted the Summer Olympics that the US boycotted. For 10 points, name this year in which Ronald Reagan defeated Jimmy Carter in the presidential election.", "answer": "1980", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This hero's birth was facilitated by a magic ring which Dame Brusen gave to King Pelles; Pelles's daughter, Elaine, used the ring to enchant this hero's father into thinking he was sleeping with his mistress. Upon joining his father's company on adulthood, this figure was the first able to sit in the Siege Perilous, foreshadowing his greatest achievement, after which he meets Joseph of Arimathea and ascends to heaven. FTP what knight of the Round Table was the illegitimate son of Lancelot, whose purity allows him to obtain the Holy Grail.", "answer": "Galahad", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "One title character created by this novelist gives up Gwendolen for Mirah after learning he's Jewish and deciding to help try to create a Jewish homeland in Palestine. Daniel Deronda was written by this novelist, who portrayed Savanarola's Bonfire of the Vanities in a novel about a title woman who learns to help others during the plague, Romola. This novelist created a title miser who raises Effie and loses his gold in Silas Marner. FTP what female novelist born Mary Ann Evans wrote those novels and Middlemarch under a male pseudonym?", "answer": "George Eliot (accept Mary Ann Evans before mentioned)", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "EEG signals in this brain structure include large irregular activity and theta rhythm. The last stage of the trisynaptic circuit in this structure includes transmissions between areas of the cornu ammonis. Neural stem cells are located in a part of this structure called the dentate gyrus. Terje Lomo discovered long-term potentiation and John O'Keefe discovered place cells in this structure, which is located in the inner region of the temporal lobe, and is part of the limbic system. Anterograde amnesia often involves atrophy of this structure, which is involved in spatial navigation and the storing of long-term memories. For 10 points, name this brain structure that resembles a seahorse.", "answer": "hippocampus [or hippocampal formation] ", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "The first title character of this opera sings about his misery in the aria \"Vois ma misere, helas,\" and its second title character sings the seduction aria \"Mon coeur s'ouvre a toi voix.\" FTPE:", "answers": ["Samson and Delilah [or Samson et Dalila]", "Camille Saint-Saens", "organ"], "parts": ["Name this opera with a bacchanale that is based on a section of The Book of Judges.", "Samson and Delilah was by this Frenchman, who also composed the tone poem Danse Macabre and the collection The Carnival of the Animals, whose movements depict a swan and tortoises, among others.", "Saint-Saens's third symphony is often named for this keyboard instrument, which is commonly found in churches, and whose sound is produced using compressed air and pipes."], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "Children must be at least seven years old and profess their belief in \u201creal presence\u201d before participating in this rite. FTPE:", "answers": ["First Communion", "Confession or Penance", "Extreme Unction"], "parts": ["What is this rite in which Catholic children first accept the bread and wine that represent the body and blood of Christ?", "Before taking First Communion, a child must take part in this action, formally known as the Sacrament of Reconciliation.", "Peter Lombard is reputed to be the first to call this final Catholic sacrament \u201cLast Rites,\u201d which is a bit of misnomer, as it can be done more than once. It involves anointing a sick person to comfort them."], "subcategory": "Religion Christianity", "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "Name some things about people and places associated with the late republic period of Rome, for 10 points each.", "answers": ["Gaius Julius Caesar", "Gaul [or Gallia]", "Vercingetorix"], "parts": ["This man became entangled in Egyptian politics and fought the Battle of the Nile to support his lover Cleopatra. He got stabbed on March 15 or something.", "This region, which included Alesia, was invaded by Caesar in 58 B.C. People from this region were the cause of the first sack of Rome in 387 BC.", "This leader from Boris Nguyen\u2019s hometown attempted to unite the Gallic Tribes but lost power after failing to hold Alesia. He was brought to Rome, paraded through the streets, and strangled to death."], "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Unferth insults this person, who responds by mentioning his swimming contest with Breca. FTPE:", "answers": ["Beowulf", "Old English [prompt on \"English\"]", "Seamus Heaney"], "parts": ["Name this literary character who helps Hrothgar by killing the monster Grendel.", "Beowulf was written in this language, which was also used for the works in the Exeter Book.", "A new verse translation of Beowulf was created in 2001 by this Irish poet, whose collection Death of a Naturalist contains the poems \"Digging\" and \"Mid-Term Break.\""], "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "The essay General Scholium [SKOH-lee-uhm] that is appended to this work contains the dictum \"Hypotheses non fingo,\" which is Latin for \"I feign no hypotheses.\" For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica", "Robert Hooke", "Edmond Halley"], "parts": ["Name this 1687 work by Isaac Newton that contains his namesake three laws of motion.", "Newton was inspired to write the Principia after this man claimed to have derived Kepler's laws of planetary motion. A law named for this man is often written as F equals negative kx.", "This man paid for the Principia to be published. A comet named for this English astronomer can be seen with the naked eye when close to the Earth, and has an average period of 76 years."], "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This man was the referee for the 1896 boxing match between Fitzsimmons and Sharkey. FTPE:", "answers": ["Wyatt Earp", "Gunfight at the O.K. Corral [or Shootout at the O.K. Corral]", "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson"], "parts": ["Name this Old West lawman who killed Frank Stilwell and was friends with Doc Holliday.", "Wyatt Earp, his two brothers, and Doc Holliday participated in this brief 1881 event on the streets of Tombstone, Arizona, that killed Frank and Tom McLaury, along with Bill Clanton.", "Wyatt Earp was also friends with this lawman, who eventually moved to New York City and became a sports reporter. Ed and Jim were the brothers of this man, who was nicknamed \"Bat.\""], "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "This book's subject performed a hemi-spherectomy on \"A Girl Named Maranda.\" FTPE:", "answers": ["Gifted Hands", "Ben Carson", "Popeye\u2019s"], "parts": ["Name this book that also details the 1987 separation of Siamese twins joined at the head thanks in part to the special ability of the titular appendages.", "The book Gifted Hands is the story of this neurosurgeon, who is celebrated in the National Great Blacks in Wax Museum, and is running for President of the United States.", "Ben Carson was once held at gunpoint at this fast-food chain, but courageously told the assailant, \"I believe that you want the guy behind the counter.\""], "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events"}, {"leadin": "This experiment was inspired by one of its two namesakes watching a slot machine. FTPE:", "answers": ["Luria\u2013Delbruck experiment [or fluctuation test]", "phages [or bacteriophages]", "E. coli [or Escherichia coli]"], "parts": ["Name this 1943 experiment that showed mutations in bacteria occur spontaneously.", "In the Luria-Delbruck experiment, the agar of petri dishes contained the T1 [T-one] example of these viruses that infect bacteria. Other examples of them include T4, Lambda, and Phi X 174.", "These bacteria were used in the Luria-Delbruck experiment. A strain of this organism called O157:H7 that produces Shiga toxins is sometimes found in undercooked ground beef."], "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "The Iki Archipelago\u2019s 23 islands belong to this country. For 10 points each", "answers": ["Japan or Nippon", "Honshu", "Hokkaido"], "parts": ["What island nation is separated from Russia by the Sea of Okhotsk and from Korea by a namesake sea?", "This island of Japan hosts cities such as Nagoya, Yokohama, and the capital, Tokyo.", "Honshu and this island are connected by the Seikan Tunnel. This island was first settled by the Ainu and its capital is Sapporo."], "subcategory": "Geography World", "category": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "This author directed his friend Max Brod to burn his unfinished works after his death, but thankfully Brod didn\u2019t. FTPE:", "answers": ["Franz Kafka", "Josef K. [both required; prompt on partial answer]", "\u201cA Hunger Artist\u201d"], "parts": ["What Czech author depicted Gregor Samsa\u2019s unexplained awakening as a vermin in The Metamorphosis?", "Kafka presents interminable proceedings leading to the stabbing execution of this character with a surname given by only a single letter in The Trial.", "The title character of this allegorical Kafka work is replaced by a panther after he starves himself to death in a cage for audiences."], "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "In a poem by Auden, this object is expected to include \"Marble well-governed cities,\" but actually includes \"A plain without a feature\" and \"No blade of grass, no sign of neighborhood.\" FTPE:", "answers": ["shield of Achilles [prompt on partial answer]", "aegis [EE-jis]", "Ajax the Great [do NOT accept \"Ajax the Lesser\"]"], "parts": ["Name this piece of armor that was made by Hephaestus and worn by the son of Thetis.", "Athena possessed this goat-skin shield, whose center included the head of Medusa.", "The shield belonging to this son of Telamon was made from seven layers of ox-hide and had an external bronze plate. His shield was often used to protect his half-brother, the archer Teucer."], "subcategory": "Mythology Greco-Roman", "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "A book about this subject focuses on the way that the exchange of objects between groups build relationships. For ten points each:", "answers": ["gifts", "Franz Boas", "Bronislaw Malinowski"], "parts": ["Identify this type of item, exchanged during the Native American potlatch ceremony, which titles a Marcel Mauss book.", "This founder of American academic anthropology studied the practice of potlatch among the Kwakiutl [kwah-kee-OOTL], which led him to develop the concept of cultural relativism.", "This Polish anthropologist examined the Trobiand islanders and discussed the kula ring in Argonauts of the Western Pacific."], "subcategory": "Social Science Anthropology", "category": "Social Science"}, {"leadin": "After the failure of the presidency of Porfirio Diaz, this event saw the election of liberal president Francisco Madero, who was assassinated two years later by conservatives. FTPE:", "answers": ["Mexican Revolution [or Revolucion Mexicana]", "Zimmerman Telegram [or Zimmermann Note]", "Ten Tragic Days [or La Decena Tragica]"], "parts": ["Name this period of upheaval that partially coincided with World War I and lasted from 1910-1920.", "This message saw the Germans ask for an alliance with the current Mexican government and promise to help the Mexicans recover their land that was lost after the Mexican-American War.", "Madero resigned and US Ambassador Henry Lane Wilson allowed Victoriano Huerta to seize power during this series of events that occurred in February of 1913."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "The azimuthal quantum number for this orbital equals zero. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["s orbital", "spheres [accept reasonable equivalents, such as balls]", "inert pair effect"], "parts": ["Name this orbital that can hold less electrons than the p, d, or f orbitals.", "Unlike p orbitals, which are shaped like dumbbells, s orbitals are shaped like these objects.", "Post-transition metals such as thallium have an oxidation state two less than their valency due to this effect, which is caused by the electrons in the outermost s orbital being difficult to ionize."], "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "For a while in the 1920s one philosopher figured he had solved all of philosophy\u2019s problems. FTPE:", "answers": ["Ludwig Wittgenstein", "\u201cThe World\u201d", "language"], "parts": ["What German thinker wrote the brief and axiomatically organized treatise titled Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus, which famously ends, \u201cWhereof one cannot speak, thereof one must be silent.\u201d", "Wittgenstein\u2019s first proposition in the Tractatus is that this entity is \u201call that is the case,\u201d suggesting the breadth of his argument.", "Wittgenstein used the idea of a beetle in a box to suggest the impossibility of a private form of this communication structure."], "subcategory": "Philosophy European", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"leadin": "This poem includes a refrain describing women who \u201ccome and go/Talking of Michelangelo.\u201d FTPE:", "answers": ["\u201cThe Love Song of J. Alfred Prufrock\u201d", "mermaids", "Eternal footman"], "parts": ["The speaker of what poem by T.S. Eliot wonders if he dares to \u201ceat a peach\u201d and apparently never asks a woman the question he had hoped to?", "At the poem\u2019s end, Prufrock notes that he has heard these female mythological creatures singing \u201ceach to each\u201d but doesn\u2019t think they will sing to him.", "Prufrock notes he was afraid when he saw this personification of death, which he describes as this type of attendant who might help one out of a carriage."], "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following about the speed of sound, for 10 points each.", "answers": ["density", "343 m/s [accept any answers between 325-361 meters per second]", "1.4 [or 7/5; accept other mathematical equivalents]"], "parts": ["The speed of sound in liquids and solids is inversely proportional to the square root of this quantity, which is symbolized by the lower case Greek letter rho, and equals mass over volume.", "Within 5%, give the speed of sound in meters per second in dry air at 20 degrees Celsius.", "The equation for the speed of sound in an ideal gas includes the adiabatic index, which has this numerical value for a diatomic gas, and is 5/3 for a monatomic gas."], "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This Italian\u2019s painting titled Nu couche or Reclining Nude recently sold for $170 million. FTPE:", "answers": ["Amadeo Modigliani", "Madonna (accept \u201cMary\u201d)", "Mannerism"], "parts": ["What early 20th century painter is known for the elongated necks he gave many of his female subjects?", "Parmigianino [pahr-mi-juh-NEE-noh] painted this traditional subject of Renaissance paintings with a long neck, holding an oddly elongated baby Jesus on her lap.", "Parmigianino was a prominent exponent of this late Renaissance style known for its use of distortion and exaggeration in bodies and spaces."], "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "John Updike\u2019s novel comprising the Reverend Tom Marshfield\u2019s journal entries is titled for a \u201cmonth of\u201d this day of the week. FTPE:", "answers": ["Sunday", "ice cream", "worms"], "parts": ["A morning on what day of the week titles a Wallace Stevens poem in which a woman enjoys \u201clate/Coffee and oranges in a sunny chair\u201d rather than the \u201chush of ancient sacrifice\u201d?", "Stevens is slightly better known for a poem describing the \u201cemperor of\u201d this sweet treat.", "Stevens wrote a poem about these lowly creatures at \u201cheaven\u2019s gate,\u201d while Hamlet told Claudius how these creatures can eventually make a progress through a king."], "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This man referred to Islam as \u201cMohammedism\u201d in his opinion for Wallace v. Jaffree, which struck down a law that let teachers lead prayers and meditations in classrooms during school. FTPE:", "answers": ["John Paul Stevens", "First Amendment", "Engel v. Vitale [accept either or both names in any order]"], "parts": ["Name this Supreme Court justice who retired in 2010 and was replaced by Elena Kagan.", "The establishment of religion in public schools violates this amendment to the US Constitution, which also covers freedom of speech and the right to peaceably assemble.", "The outcome of this 1962 Supreme Court case deemed state-authorized prayer at the start of each school day unconstitutional."], "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}]}